The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
The Führer President has returned?!
大総統が戻ってきた
I heard he destroyed a tank from Briggs at the main gate.
正門でブリッグズの戦車を破壊したそうだ
That'll show those monkeys from Briggs!
ざまぁみろ　ブリッグズの山猿め
残りの兵士を集めよう
Let's gather the rest of the soldiers.
作戦本部の奪還だ
We need to recapture mission headquarters!
Yeah!
おう
大総統が正門に
The Führer President is at the main gate?
Oh.
ほう　生で見るのは初めてだわい
It's my first time seeing him with my own eyes.
こやつが　我が孫娘の腕をちぎりよった男か
So he's the one who ripped off my granddaughter's arm...!
I see.
へえ 一般人を犠牲にして
So you were planning on sacrificing all the civilians
so that you high-level officials would gain immortality,
あんたら高官が不老不死を得て
and unify the world.
世界を統一するねぇ
Is Führer President Bradley doing everything
even with the knowledge of what you all are up to?
ブラッドレイ大総統も分かってやっているのですか
He's the leader of this country,
and was made for that purpose.
そのためにつくられたこの国のリーダーだ
Why are you hesitating?!
何をためらう
We're planning on creating a world without war!
戦いのない世界をつくるのだ
So you're saying the world should be destroyed once for that purpose?
そのために一度滅びろって
It's not destruction, but rather regeneration.
滅びではない再生だ
It's the 'reconstruction' stage that you alchemists refer to.
お前たち錬金術師の言う再構築だ
一般国民に与えられるのは死ではない
The civilians aren't going to be given 'death'.
They're going to receive the honor of living within us forever!
我々の中で永遠に生き続けられるのだ
And we're going to unify the world together!
そして共に世界を一つに統べる
All is one, and one is all!
全は一　一は全
We, the chosen ones of Amestris, will become one and-
我々アメストリスの選ばれし者が一となり
すべてを
だってさ　あんたたちどうする
You heard him.
What will you guys do?
They're trying to gain everything for themselves.
こいつらだけいい思いしようとしているのよ
Are you just going to let him go?
ほっとくの
C-Come along with me, you all.
お前たち　私についてこい
If you do, I'll ask that man to-
そうすればあのお方に口利きして
I'm a soldier, so I must obey the orders of my superiors.
自分は軍人ですから
上官の命令には従わなければなりません
しかし正直　もう何を信じたらいいのか
But to be honest, I don't know what to believe anymore...
この期に及んでまだ迷っていられるとはな
You're still hesitating in this situation?
信じられもしない上官に付き従っていても
Obeying a superior you can't even believe doesn't make you loyal.
それは忠誠とは言わん
ただの自己欺瞞だ
You're just fooling yourself.
自分を信じなよ
Believe in yourselves.
自分自身の魂に
Just choose a way of living that won't shame your soul.
恥をかかせない生き方を選べばいいじゃない
I have family in the city.
町に家族がいるんだ
オレもだ
So do I.
I, too, as well.
自分もです
准将殿
Brigadier General,
これが我々の答えです
this is our answer.
Mission headquarters, what's the situation?
作戦本部　状況は
Not too great.
芳しくないですね
The Central Soldiers have begun to recover in several areas.
各所で中央兵が息を吹き返しています
閣下は今どちらで
Where are you right now, General?
The Führer President's office.
大総統執務室だ
And the survivors?
生存者は
執務室周辺の味方と連絡が取れなくなっています
We haven't been able to get in touch with our men who are around the office.
There's a high possibility that there are many Central Soldiers surrounding it.
そこは中央兵に囲まれている可能性が高いですね
分かった　そっちも危険が迫ったら逃げろ
Roger.
If things get dangerous over there, run.
私のことは捨てていけ
Just leave me behind.
アイ マム
Aye, Ma'am.
さて　再びここは敵だらけになった
Now, this place has become filled with enemies again.
中央兵が隊を整えてここに踏み込んでくるのも
It's only a matter of time until the Central Soldiers form up and storm this place.
時間の問題だ
となると
Which means...
After going down a bit,
ある程度下りたら
I'll dig a side tunnel as an escape route, just like I did when I came here.
来たときみたいに脱出用の横穴を掘るわ
Escape...
脱出
一緒にどう
Why don't we escape together?
あなたたちも
You all could probably use some time to recover and plan, couldn't you?
いったん態勢を立て直した方がいいでしょ
近いな
He's close.
You think so too?
やっぱそう思うか
You two can sense him?
あなたたち　気配で分かるの
It's more of a "bad feeling".
イヤな予感ってやつだよ
手ひどくやられた古傷がうずくっつうか
Like the feeling you get when a bad scar starts aching.
Oh my, do I have guests?
おやおや　こんな所にギャラリーが来るとは
I'm a little nervous.
緊張してしまうね
誰だ
Who are you?!
Me?
私かね
Hmm...
The man who created King Bradley...
キング·ブラッドレイをつくった男
といったところかな
...perhaps?
The Führer President...
大総統を
ということはそっち側の人間か
Which means you're on their side.
Huh? You're...
おや 君は
I thought you were at the radio station,
but you actually took the effort to come here.
ラジオ局にいるものと思っていたが
わざわざ出向いてくれるとはね
Thanks for giving me one less thing to do, Mustang.
手間が省けて助かるよ　マスタング君
Guys, entertain them for a while.
お前たち少し相手をしてやりなさい
Who the hell are they?!
なんだこいつら
Dolls?!
人形兵
いや　あれとは明らかに動きが違う
No...
Their movements clearly differ from the dolls!
They're men who might have become King Bradley.
キング·ブラッドレイになっていた
かもしれない男たちだよ
They were gathered as soon as they were born,
生まれてすぐに集められ
大総統になる
and they were given special education and training
ただそれだけのために
for the sole purpose of becoming the Führer President.
専門の教育と訓練の中で育てられた者たち
And with the twelfth experiment, King Bradley was born.
そして １２番目の実験で
キング·ブラッドレイが誕生した
So these are...!
では この者たちは
余り物だよ
The leftovers.
もっとも彼らはずっと戦闘訓練を積んできた
Despite that, they've been training for battle all this time.
Although they're not as powerful as King Bradley,
キング·ブラッドレイほどではないが
they're pretty good.
強いぞ
Damn...
くそ　反乱軍め
...those rebels...!
Shit, I passed out.
いかん　気絶しておったわ
大尉
Captain!
That's right...
そうだった
If I were to pull it out, I'd probably die from blood loss.
抜くとかえって失血死するか
ブラッドレイ
Bradley...!
あでっ
That was close, old man!
危ねぇな　じいさん
わざとではありま　ないわい
It was an accident, youn-
It wasn't on purpose!
あっ この
You-
As I thought, prey like you gets my heart pumping faster.
やはり　こういう得物の方がしっくりくる
I'm surprised you put up such a good fight despite being more aged than I.
私より年寄りなのに　よく動いたものだ
But...!
だが
It ends here!
これで終わりだ
じいさん
Gramps!
若
シンの皇子か
The prince from Xing, eh?
Dammit, Lin!
てめぇ　リン
Quit taking over without asking!
勝手に出てくんな
You're just like the girl who cut her own arm off.
前に腕を斬り落とした女のときと同じだな
またそうして捨てられないもののために
Just like her, you endanger your life for something you can't throw away.
己の命を危険にさらす
Young master...
若
この戦えぬ老いぼれなど捨てなされ
I can no longer fight. Just throw me away...
バカ言うな
Quit joking!
Are you telling me to become a man like him?!
オレにあの男と同じになれというのか
王は民のためにあるもの
A king exists for his people.
民なくして王はありえない
Without his people, there is no king.
He's planning on abandoning the people of his country.
あいつは自分の国の民をも見捨てようとしている
That's not someone I want to become!
あれはオレの目指しているものとは違う
王としてあるまじき男ですか
A man unworthy of being called 'king', huh...
Then we must defeat him.
それは倒さねばなりません
Don't speak!
しゃべるな　休んでろ
Take a break!
I agree.
そうですな　休みを暇を頂きましょう
I'll take a break...
I shall rest.
なっ
Harden, Greed!
硬化しろグリード
若の体を守れ
Protect the young master's body!
R-Right!
Young master...
若　王になりなされよ
Become king.
It's time for this old geezer to begin his eternal rest!
この老いぼれは
ここで永遠の暇をちょうだいいたす
Idiot!!
バ
バカ野郎
You're coming to hell with me,
地獄へつきあってもらうぞ
Bradley!!
ブラッドレイ
この命懸けても
I can't give him a single wound, even by risking my life?
傷一つ付けられぬというのか
Young master...
若　面目ありませぬ
I'm so sorry...
Even if you possess the eyes of God,
たとえ神のごとき目を持っていようとも
見えない所からの攻撃は防ぎようがあるまい
you can't possibly dodge an attack coming from somewhere you can't see!
Old man, I'll... be going...
じいさん
地獄への道行き
to hell with you...
つきあってやるぜぇ
おおっ かたじけな…い
I'm so grateful...
Grandpa!!!
爺様
ったく　溝にはまるわ　街灯に激突するわ
Jesus!
First you get stuck in a ditch,
then you ram into a lightpost?!
つくづく運転ヘタだな　チョロひげ
You really suck at driving!
うるさい
Shut it!
あんなボロ車でここまで来れただけ有り難く思え
Be thankful that we were able to get this far in a beat up car like that!
こんなとこまで来てケンカしない
We've come this far! Stop fighting!
とにかく　早く地下に入る場所を見つけるんだ
Anyway, we need to hurry up and find a place where we can get underground.
あれは
That's...
マスタング大佐だろうか
Colonel Mustang?
うまくやってりゃいいが
I hope they're doing well.
兄さん
Brother...
急ごう
Let's hurry!
こいつら
How non-human can your movements get?!
人間離れしてるにも程があんだろうがぁ
背中ががら空きですよ　大佐
Colonel, your back is wide open.
任せている部下がいるので　ついね
There's someone I've entrusted my back to, so yeah.
真理の扉
The gate of truth.
錬金術の禁忌とされる人体錬成
Human transmutation, a taboo in alchemy.
それを試みた術師は真理の扉を開くことになる
Alchemists who try it end up opening the gate of truth,
それ相応の通行料を払ってね
paying a befitting toll.
エルリック兄弟が
So that's how the Elric Brothers sacrificed their bodies?
己の肉体を犠牲にしたというあれのことか
あなたも
Did you do it too?
中を少し持ってかれたわ
They took a bit of my insides.
けど　そこまでして分かったのは
But what I learned from all that,
結局　人体錬成なんて成功しないってことだった
is that human transmutation never works.
あらやだ　こんな話軍人さんには興味なかったかしらね
Oh my, soldiers like yourselves probably aren't interested in tales like these.
なんの
Not true.
その真理の扉とやらを開けた人間こそ
Humans who have opened the gate of truth are the "human sacrifices" they speak of.
彼奴らの言う人柱
敵の企みを知る手がかりになるかもしれません
You may have a handhold in finding out what they are up to.
その真理の扉を開けてまで
So you all had someone you wanted to see again,
自分の肉体を犠牲にしてまで
even if you had to open the gate of truth and sacrifice your body.
再会したかった相手があなた方にいたと
あなたには
What about you?
どんな代償を払ってでも　もう一度会いたいと思える人
Do you have someone that you'd give up anything for just to see again?
それこそ軍人には無縁の話
Now that's something that means nothing to a soldier.
死んだ者への未練など無意味
Having regret for the deceased is pointless.
死なせないために戦うのみです
We fight in order to keep them alive.
そりゃそうだわね
That's true.
ですが
But...
少し分かったような気もする
...I feel like I understand something now.
エドワード·エルリック
Edward Elric.
初めて会ったとき
When I first met him, I threatened him and told him to tell me everything he knows,
知っていることを何もかも話せと脅しましたが
あの少年は幼なじみを人質に取られていることを
but that boy didn't say a word about his old friend having been taken hostage.
決して口にしなかった
ただひと言
Just one line:
察してくれと
"Please try to realize."
あの目は我々軍人のそれとも
Those eyes were different from those of us soldiers,
ましてや軍の狗と呼ばれる錬金術師のそれとも違った
or even those of State Alchemists,
who are referred to as the dogs of the military.
強いて言えば
If I had to say, they were eyes that didn't want to lose anything important to them again no matter what...
これ以上何があっても大切なものを失うまいとする
聞き分けのない子供の目
Eyes of an unreasonable child?
あのまっすぐな目に
I'd be lying if I said that those straightforward eyes didn't move my heart.
心動かされなかったと言えばうそになる
しかし　その愚直なまでの思いが
But will those naïvely honest feelings of his
find a way out of the difficulty in this fight,
果たしてこの戦いで活路を開くのか
あるいは　あだとなるか
or will they come back to harm him?
これでよし
There.
さあ そろそろ始めようか
Let us begin.
１６号 １７号
Number 16,
Number 17,
２１号 ２３号 ２６号
Number 21,
Number 23, Number 26.
おいで
Come here.
なんだ
What?!
いくよ
Here we go!
何をした
What did you do?!
何　ただの第１段階だよ
This is just the first step.
このセントラルに
Do you know how many alchemy research facilities under direct control of the Führer President exist in Central?
大総統府直轄の錬金術研究所が
いくつあるか知っているかね
今使われているのは市内に４か所
There should be four that are currently being used...
いや
No!
第五研究所
Research Laboratory 5...
５か所
There are five!
５つの頂点を持つ
A transmutation circle with five points!
錬成陣
まさか　あのカーブした地下通路
Could it be that the curving underground path was a circle that connects the research facilities?!
研究所をつなぐ円を描いていたというの
なんだ
What?!
どうしたの　ハインケルさん
What's wrong, Mr. Heinkel?
イズミ
Izumi.
Yeah.
どうやらここらがいいとこみたいね
Seems like this is a good spot.
この壁から脱出用の穴を掘るわ
I'm going to dig a hole for escape purposes in this wall.
ちょっと離れてて
Stand back.
ではここでお別れだ
Then this is where we say goodbye.
我々はまだここに残って戦わねばならん
We still need to remain here and fight.
ここから先こそがおそらく敵の中枢
From here on out is probably the enemy's backbone.
みすみす急襲の好機を逃すわけにはいきませんのでな
We can't just let our chance to ambush them go to waste.
あなたたち
You...
いろいろ世話になった
Thanks for all your help.
ありがとう　イズミ·カーティス
We're in your debt, Izumi Curtis.
こちらこそ　アームストロング少…
I should be saying that, Major General Arm-
な…
何
What?!
アルフォンス君
Alphonse!
イズミ
Izumi!
Izumi!!
は　鋼の
F-Fullmetal...!
このぉ
Dammit...!!
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
Anger is born at the extremities of sorrow,
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第５８話　『ひとばしら』
and when two souls dwell within a single body,
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
死してなお　守り続けるが
the annihilations begins.
その本懐
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 58, Sacrifices.
Continuing to protect even after death is their long-cherished plan.